<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Stephen Mariano</title>
 <link href="smcabrera.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="smcabrera.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2014-06-20T19:02:00-05:00</updated>
 <id>smcabrera.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Mark Otto</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Remote Pairing Tools</title>
   <link href="smcabrera.github.io/2014/06/20/remote-pairing-tools/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>smcabrera.github.io/2014/06/20/remote-pairing-tools</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve recently been on the lookout for tools to make remote pair
programming easier. My main motivations are the following&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pair programming, particularly with someone better than you (most
programmers at this point!) is the best way to learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My goal is to work remotely as a developer so I want to get a good
comfortable remote setup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;m currently engaged in an &lt;a href=&quot;www.bloc.io&quot;&gt;apprenticeship&lt;/a&gt; heavily focused on remote
pair programming. So now it&amp;#39;s urgent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s what I&amp;#39;ve found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;remote server with ssh and tmux&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tmux, short for terminal multiplexer lets you run multiple terminals
within one environment. It&amp;#39;s sort of like browser tabs for your
terminal. For remote pairing you can use it to connect to a remote
server via a secure shell or ssh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a pretty detailed description of the process &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeespencer.com/articles/building-a-remote-pairing-setup/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; using prgmr.com as the remote server. I haven&amp;#39;t tried it so I won&amp;#39;t go into the process here but needless to say that setting it up is pretty involved. There&amp;#39;s a description of something similar in the book from a book on the topic from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pragprog.com/book/jkrp/remote-pairing&quot;&gt;Pragmatic Bookshelf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tmux is the clear winner for my current use case&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Pros:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works great on linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works great with vim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works great on &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;low-bandwidth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. This is huge for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Cons&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pair needs to be using a console editor like vim or emacs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corllary to above--if you use vim and they use emacs, not so great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may want to maniuplate the browser console together or do other
screen sharing that doesn&amp;#39;t involve the console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll have to find other solutions for when tmux isn&amp;#39;t an option (screen sharing for when we want to look at what something looks like in a browser for instance) but I think that most of the time some kind of a tmux session solution is going to be the way to go (the prag programmers book also talks about different ways to do this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Simpler Solution: tmate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tmate.io/&quot;&gt;tmate&lt;/a&gt;: A fork of tmux, designed to do the
above configuration automatically. As far as I can tell:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Pros:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much easier setup--most of the work is already done for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Cons:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The other person has to use your tmux configurations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#39;re stuck using ssh, instead of mosh (which is apparently faster than ssh).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I imagine, though I&amp;#39;m not positive, that you wouldn&amp;#39;t be able to use some of aforementioned tmux plugins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Other Tools to try out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mosh.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;mosh&lt;/a&gt; SSH alternative. Uses less bandwidth and thus faster than ssh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zolrath/wemux&quot;&gt;wemux&lt;/a&gt;: tmux plugin for remote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pairing--need to check it out and see what kind of features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/benmills/vimux&quot;&gt;vimux&lt;/a&gt;: ditto.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tmuxinator/tmuxinator&quot;&gt;tmuxinator&lt;/a&gt;: Looks like it
can be useful for saving a lot of settings (for a project) without
having to restart it each time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#39;t tried any of this yet, but I&amp;#39;ll be giving these a shot and write about how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Starting Bloc</title>
   <link href="smcabrera.github.io/2014/06/15/starting%20bloc/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>smcabrera.github.io/2014/06/15/starting bloc</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I officially begin my apprenticeship with &lt;a href=&quot;bloc.io&quot;&gt;Bloc&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#39;m pretty excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is Bloc? It&amp;#39;s an intensive course for learning the skills to be a professional web developer. Its part of a movement of companies designed to give people the professional skills to find employment in the tech industry via short but intensive study in immediately marketable skills, rather than the traditional multi-year degree-based educational model. Typically these programming &amp;quot;bootcamps&amp;quot; involve dropping $12,000 for three months of studying 40 to 50 hours a week in a classroom in major urban tech hub like San Francisco or New York. It sounds kind of crazy on the surface of it, but it seems to be working. There&amp;#39;s a huge demand for people with the skills these bootcamps are offering in a field where degrees matter less than ability and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile ever since the aborted start of my career in economic development I&amp;#39;ve been trying to forge a new career path studying online. I first fell in love with programming with a coursera course I took called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coursera.org/course/interactivepython&quot;&gt;Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python&lt;/a&gt; and the rest is history. But after a year of studying on my own, I finally decided that I&amp;#39;d like to do something more intensive and get a little more guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter Bloc. Bloc takes this idea of intensive professional courses and moves them to the web. Instead of sitting in a classroom for 8 hours a day, the instruction takes place on an online platform. The human element takes place through the use of mentors--professional developers who dedicate time each week to meeting one-on-one with each of their students and providing some guidance for the process. The advantage of this setup is that I can do it right where I am now, from Lima Peru. This means a much lower cost both in terms of the cost of the program and in the costs of quitting my job and moving to an (expensive) North American city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also suspect the mentor format might just be better than the traditional classroom format.  Learning, particularly learning development, takes place by doing. Compared to university education, thie teacher role in this setting seems less like a college lecturer and more like your thesis advisor--you meet periodically to go over your work and receive feedback and then you go back to your desk and work on your own. Being more independent and less structured is definitely challenging, but when I think back upon my experience in writing my senior thesis, I remember it as one of the times where I learned the most in all my time in college and was the most useful when applying for jobs. So I&amp;#39;m optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education and &lt;em&gt;learning&lt;/em&gt; generally are areas that interest me a great deal. I&amp;#39;m very excited to see the ways that technology can transform education, so I expect I&amp;#39;ll have quite a bit to comment on as I go through Bloc. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
